intercargo.org 2017-02-22

# Privacy Policy

### Our Commitment To Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

### The Information We Collect

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the INTERCARGO website at www.intercargo.org. On some pages, you can make requests, and register to receive information. The types of personal information collected at these pages are:

  * Personal Name
  * Organisation Name/Type
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Telephone numbers

We maintain databases on State control inspections and experiences when loading and unloading dry bulk cargoes at Terminals. The information collected is limited to that identified on the relevant forms.

You may elect to join INTERCARGO by submitting an online form. The information collected is limited to that identified on the relevant forms, and will be stored in membership databases.

Our webserver is not set up to generally track, collect or distribute personal information about its visitors. It does recognise the home server of visitors, but not email addresses. For example, we can tell which Internet Service Provider our visitors use, but not the names, addresses or other information about our visitors that would allow us to identify the particular visitors to our sites. This information is used only for internal purposes. For example, we compile statistics that show the daily number of visitors to our sites, the daily requests we receive for particular files on our web sites, and what countries those requests come from. These aggregated statistics are used internally to better provide services to the members and may also be provided to others, but again, the statistics contain no personal information and cannot be used to gather such information.

We do, however, collect additional information, such as, but not limited to Internet IP addresses when accessing the Member's only areas of the site.

### The Way We Use Information

WE DO NOT SELL, TRADE, EXCHANGE OR OTHERWISE MAKE AVAILABLE ANY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO ANY OTHER COMPANY OR ORGANISATION, except where it is explicitly stated that information may be shared (for example in the Inspection Reporting form).

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

### How We use "Cookies"

A Cookie is a piece of text asking permission to be placed in your device's memory or hard drive. If you agree, then your browser saves the text in a small file. Our Membership administration system uses cookies to remember your login information and statistical information about your visit. These cookies allow the system to respond to you as an individual, for example logging you back in without having to re-enter a user name and password. **The members area of the site will not work correctly without cookies enabled**.

You may set your web browser to notify you of cookie placement requests or decline cookies completely. You can delete the files that contain cookies; those files are stored as part of your Internet browser under the website address www.intercargo.org

### Our Commitment To Data Security

To prevent unauthorised access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information

You can access all the personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain on request to [info@intercargo.org](mailto:info@INTERCARGO.org?Subject=Request%20for%20privacy%20information%20)  You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by sending us a request that credibly shows error. 

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.
